Finding Aid for the Albert Boime Papers LSC.1834
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Correspondence, 1963-2008
  - Subseries 6.2: Specific correspondence, 1963-2002
    - Burlington correspondence, 1977 (Box 125, Folder 7)
      General correspondence, art newsletter, Boime's curriculum vitae, correspondence with Benedict Nicholson regarding an article by Boime for The Burlington Magazine, and photos.
    - Skirball Cultural Center correspondence, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 8)
      Notes, articles, and correspondence.
    - Correspondence from museums and businesses, 1989-1990 (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - National Geographic, 1997-1998 (Box 125, Folder 10)
      Correspondence and invoices for consulting Boime performed in relation to a Van Gogh article.
    - Cornelia Harrison Stranahan, 1975-1976 (Box 125, Folder 11)
      Correspondence and photocopy regarding Cornelia Harrison Stranahan. Correspondents include Charles Scribner.
    - Alex Seltzer, 1977 (Box 125, Folder 12)
      Correspondence from Alex Seltzer, a graduate student.
    - Colleague correspondence, 1986, 1992-1996, 2000-2002 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - 19th century, undated (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Maler Gerard (1 of 2) (Box 125, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Maler Gerard und Frau Susanne, images, and clippings. All materials in French and German.
    - Maler Gerard (2 of 2), 1988-1998 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Wayne Andersen (1 of 3), 1990-1992 (Box 126, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with Boime and correspondence regarding U.S. fellowships and teaching appointments. Other materials include drafts "Cezanne as Amorous Shepherd," "The Nightmare of Fuseli's Nightmare," "California Funk and the American Express," "Cezanne's L'Eternel Feminin and the Miracle of her Restored Vision," "The Extramundane Cezanne," "Relics of Paul Cezanne," "Solo Notes for the Chorus," and "Barthes, Krauss, Water, Glass, Ice and Windowpanes." Folder also includes a catalog of Andersen paintings and draft of Andersen's manuscript "Cezanne's Choice of Paris: Schapiro's Amorous Shepherd: An Essay on a Psychoanalytical Interpretation of Still-life" and a manuscript on Roman statuary for Boime to review.
    - Wayne Andersen (2 of 3), 1990-1992 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to be reviewed, bulk 1995-1999, 1970-1980 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - To answer immediately, 1980 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Wayne Andersen (3 of 3), 1990-1992 (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 6.3: General correspondence, 1964-2008
    Materials include typed and handwritten correspondence that Boime compiled by date. Materials relate to a wide range of topics. Folder contents and categories are strictly based on Boime's filing system. The subseries is arranged by date, beginning with the earliest materials.
    - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 126, Folder 6)
      Correspondence regarding article submissions and image requests, applications for research grants, notes, postcards, and Arizona Highways catalog.
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 127, Folder 4)
      Correspondence and invoices. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 127, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with colleagues during Boime's time at SUNY Binghamton, Williams College, and early years at UCLA. Materials include correspondence and notes on research pursuits, photos, letters from colleagues requesting letters of support, and some publishing correspondence with Arete.
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 127, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include Susan Perry, Mary Milton, Alain de Leiris, and Mort Grant. Folder also includes miscellaneous artist biographies, likely composed by Boime.
    - Correspondence, bulk 1971-1972, 1969 (Box 127, Folder 8)
      Correspondents include Madeleine Fidell Beaufort and Shica Greenberg. Other materials include notes and postcards. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 127, Folder 9)
      Notes and correspondence regarding issues such as the artist's role as an entrepreneur.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1978, 1982, 1991 (Box 127, Folder 10)
      Correspondence about lectures, articles, and research by Boime.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 127, Folder 11)
      Correspondents include Gerald M. Ackermann, Madeleine Beaufort Fidell, and Carl Goldstein.
    - Correspondence, bulk 1974, 1972-1973 (Box 127, Folder 12)
      Correspondents include James Welch, Jacques Foucart, John Maass, Gustav Stresow, and Marchal Landgren. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, bulk 1975-1978, 1972-1973 (Box 127, Folder 14)
      Photographic reprints and correspondence. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 127, Folder 15)
      Draft of "Poetic Technique and Meaning in La Fontaine's Fables" by Carrol F. Coates, correspondence, and draft of "One Gem of a Parable: Lessing's Ring Re-Examined" by M. Nirenberg.
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 128, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, photos, and slides. Correspondents include Rosemary Polito of the Century City Cultural Commission.
    - Correspondence, 1982, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 2)
      Correspondence from North Carolina Museum of Art about records for paintings. Some materials in Italian.
    - Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 128, Folder 4)
      Correspondence regarding lectures, research inquiries, and recommendations for students and colleagues. Invoice moved to redacted materials.
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 128, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include Maler Gerard, H.D. (Buzz) Burrows, Lawrence Fane, and Jerry Howe. Folder contains some slides.
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 128, Folder 6)
      Correspondence regarding Macchiaioli show.
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 128, Folder 7)
      Postcards and correspondence.
    - Correspondence, bulk 1986-1988, 1984 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 128, Folder 9)
      Correspondence and pottery brochure. Materials in German.
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 10)
      Correspondence regarding the Wittkower Symposium, French Bicentennial celebration, and Gerard Maler.
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      Notes, draft of paper for review, postcards, brochures, draft of "Leaves of Grass and Real Allegory," correspondence regarding manuscripts, and Graham Modern exhibition announcements. Materials in French.
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      Correspondence from Maler Gerard, letters of recommendation for students, letters from colleagues, correspondence regarding Smithsonian Regents Fellowship, and evaluation of Boime and Art History 54.
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 129, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with colleagues and friends and photographic permissions. Correspondents include Andrew Brainerd.
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 129, Folder 4)
      Correspondence regarding Tanner Symposium and art museums. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 5)
      Correspondence regarding publications. Some materials in German.
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 130, Folder 1)
      Correspondence and student recommendations (some from colleagues), and conference correspondence.
    - Correspondence, bulk 1995, 1994 (Box 130, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with colleagues, letters of recommendation for students and colleagues, and informational/research inquiries. Correspondents include Radu Bogdan. Some materials in French and Hebrew.
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      Correspondence regarding student recommendations & letters of recommendation for Boime. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1996-2002 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include John Adler and Paul Weinberg. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 130, Folder 6)
      Correspondence regarding the promotion of Oscar Vasquez.
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 130, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include Ken Aptekar and Joel Swerdlow. Materials include cards, postcards, and notes. Some materials in French.
    - Clippings and correspondence, 1998 (Box 130, Folder 8)
      Clippings regarding the work of Randall Lake and correspondence from Vivien Fryd regarding teaching positions.
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 130, Folder 9)
      Thank you letters.
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 10)
      Correspondence regarding students and images for books. Other materials include cards & postcards.
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 11)
      Correspondence from Catherine Schaller and copy of an article by Schaller. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 1)
      Correspondence regarding publications. Correspondents include Wayne Andersen, colleagues, and students.
    - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 2)
      Notes, cards, and letters regarding publications. Correspondents include Ernst Reusch.
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 131, Folder 3)
      Notes, cards, and letters regarding publications. Correspondents include Andrew Brainerd.
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 4)
      Notes, cards, and letters regarding publications. Correspondents include colleagues and students. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 5)
      Thank you notes from student groups.
    - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 131, Folder 6)
      Notes, cards, and letters regarding publications. Correspondents include colleagues and students.
    - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 131, Folder 8)
      Notes, cards, and letters regarding publications. Correspondents include colleagues and students. Folder also includes a catalog of works by Ib Benoh.
    - Correspondence, 2007 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 131, Folder 10)
      E-mail and letter from Princeton University Press.
    - Redacted materials - confidential, undated (Box 131, Folder 11)
      Folder includes redacted pages with confidential information. The bulk of materials are pages from student papers with grades.
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 145, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include Gerald M. Ackermann (Jerry), Shica Greenberg, Francis Haskell, Alfred Neumeyer, and Bob Rosenbloom. Other materials include a contract for "The Academy and French Painting in the 19th Century." Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 145, Folder 9)
      Correspondents include Gerald M. Ackermann (Jerry), Francis Haskell, and Shica Greenberg. Materials pertain to "Art and the Academy" and "Couture and the Eclectic Vision." Some materials in French and German.
    - Correspondence, bulk 1979, 1974 (Box 145, Folder 10)
      Correspondence regarding Gabriele Sprigath and her political affiliations. Correspondents include Madeleine Fidell Beaufort and Susan Sontag. Folder also includes notes. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence (1 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (2 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (3 of 3), 1979-1981 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, bulk 1982, 1981-1984 (Box 146, Folder 4)
      Correspondents include Gabriel Weisberg, Beverly Twitchell, Richard Schiff, and Andrew Brainerd. Folder also includes sabbatical leave paperwork. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 146, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include Madeleine Fidell Beaufort, Joseph Anthony, Gabriel Weisberg, and Krzysztof Pomian. Folder also includes photos. Some materials in French.
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 146, Folder 6)
- Series 7: Audio and audiovisual materials, 1974-2005
  This series is composed exclusively of audio and audiovisual materials from the 2010 addition. This includes 3 VHS tapes, 65 audiocassettes, 1 Hi8, and 7 16mm film reels containing music, lectures, language learning materials, films, and conference recordings. The film reels have been digitized by Chloe Patton in 2018 and Carton 154 contains her notes and original documentation. The film is an approximately 30-minute examination of contemporary realism via interview with various artists. The folder titles are based on the labels provided by Boime.
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audio and audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - VHS: "Merry Christmas! Macchiaoili: Painters of Italian Life. The Donn Sigerson Foundation", 1986 (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - VHS: "Picasso. 2 Versions", undated (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - VHS: "Wagner, The Ring. No. 2 continued on cassette No. 4", undated (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassette: "Albert Bug, All My Love, Pam", undated (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Audiocassette: "Bryson, Norman. Art in Context", undated (Box 152, Folder 2)
  - Audiocassette: "The Century Speaks - No. 11: Money - Short-changed?", undated (Box 152, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassette: "Getting By in Chinese I", 1983 (Box 152, Folder 4)
  - Audiocassette: "Contragate: The Secret Team", circa 1987 (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Audiocassette: "Czech Language", 1988 (Box 152, Folder 6)
  - Audiocassette: "ESL Through Music #1", 1991 May (Box 152, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassette: "Jules Feiffer", undated (Box 152, Folder 8)
  - Audiocassette: "Gaia, Wanderer", undated (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - Audiocassette: "Just Listen 'n Learn. Greek. Unit 1", 1982 (Box 152, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassette: "Just Listen 'n Learn. Greek. Unit 2", 1982 (Box 152, Folder 11)
  - Audiocassette: "Just Listen 'n Learn. Greek. Unit 3", 1982 (Box 152, Folder 12)
  - Audiocassette: "C. Greenburg", 1990 October 14 (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - Audiocassette: "C. Greenburg", 1991 December 14 (Box 152, Folder 14)
  - Audiocassette: "The Harder They Come. Original Soundtrack Recording", 1983 (Box 152, Folder 15)
  - Audiocassette: "Japanese at a Glance", 1985 (Box 152, Folder 16)
  - Audiocassette: "Jethro Tull. Crest of a Knave", 1987 (Box 152, Folder 17)
  - Audiocassette: "Kamran", 2005 June 14 (Box 152, Folder 18)
  - Audiocassette: "Kamran III", 2005 May 10 (Box 152, Folder 19)
  - Audiocassette: "Kamran IV", 2005 May 17 (Box 152, Folder 20)
  - Audiocassette: "Lehman, Harold interview", 2002 September 29 (Box 152, Folder 21)
  - Audiocassette: "Lehman, Harold interview", 2002 September 29 (Box 152, Folder 22)
  - Audiocassette: "The Lost Manet", 1996 September 15 (Box 152, Folder 23)
  - Audiocassette: "Neiman", 1998 October 5 (Box 152, Folder 24)
  - Audiocassette: "October 26", undated (Box 152, Folder 25)
  - Audiocassette: "Otto Karl Werckmeister. Getty Center. Straightforward Art History.", 1993 June 7 (Box 152, Folder 26-27)
  - Audiocassette: "Phish Set II. Amy's Farm. Auburn, ME.", 1991 August 3 (Box 152, Folder 28)
  - Audiocassette: "Quirks and Quarks", 1985 October 12 (Box 152, Folder 29)
  - Audiocassette: "R.E.M. Green", 1988 (Box 152, Folder 30)
  - Audiocassette: "Rick's tape #1. Air Supply", undated (Box 152, Folder 31)
  - Audiocassette: "Sculpture in Historical Humanistic Terms", 1990 (Box 152, Folder 32)
  - Audiocassette: "Social Oppression and the Family", 1994 (Box 152, Folder 33)
  - Audiocassette: "Some Songs", 1999 April 29 (Box 152, Folder 34)
  - Audiocassette: "Living Spanish Lessons", undated (Box 152, Folder 35)
  - Audiocassette: "Spanish 2", undated (Box 152, Folder 36)
  - Audiocassette: "Spanish III", undated (Box 152, Folder 37)
  - Audiocassette: "Surface Tension. 86/10. Comet Fever/20th C. Masters", 1986 December 4 (Box 152, Folder 38)
  - Audiocassette: "Uptones and Mix (Ska)", undated (Box 152, Folder 39)
  - Audiocassette: "Wilson, Fred", undated (Box 152, Folder 40)
  - Unlabeled audiocassettes, undated (Box 153)
    Box 153 contains 25 unlabeled audiocassettes and 1 Hi8 tapes.
  - Unlabeled Hi8, undated (Box 153)
  - 16mm film: Ithaca College. The State of Contemporary Realism. A-Roll, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 1)
  - 16mm film: The State of Contemporary Realism B-Roll, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 2)
  - 16mm film: The State of Contemporary Realism B-Negative Track, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 3)
  - 16mm film: The State of Contemporary Realism Mixed Mag Track, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 4)
  - 16mm film: the Emergence of New Realism - Focus Credits A-Roll, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 5)
  - 16mm film: The Emergence of New Realism - Focus Credits B-Roll, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 6)
  - 16mm film: The State of Contemporary Realism Release Print Old Titles, 1974 (Carton 154, Reel 7)